

# Thanh Hai Chau

**Electrical & Electronics Engineer** 

# Profile

Underwater Robotics, Electronic Design Engineer, with over 1 year of experience PCB Designer / Board Architecture (stack up) / Schematic Capture / Assembly and Fabrication Drawings. Accomplishing custom printed circuit board design for many research projects especially for autonomous underwater vehicles. Being a young engineer with enthusiastic and passion, I can work in highvolume workflow, with creative problem resolution capabilities. Seeking a position where my experience, capabilities and passion will enable me to contribute to a company's objective.

# Work Experience

# Electronics Engineer at Ho Chi Minh University of Technology, Ho Chi Minh City

**NOVEMBER 2018 - PRESENT** 

- Schematic capture and printed circuit board layout using Altium.
- Responsible of creating printed circuit board footprints / land patterns using Altium. Designed of multi-layer PCB.
- Experienced in power distribution network (PDN) issues such as ground bounce, rail collapse, cross-talk, and EMI issues.
- Understand in signal integrity problems in high-speed PCB.
- Addressed/resolved signal noises in multi-layer PCB.
- Designed of H-Bridge for 600 Brush-less DC Motor.
- Designed of Electrical Systems for Underwater Robots.
- Brought forth a hard-work ethic and self-motivated attitude.

# Vice Leader at Bach Khoa Robotics and Automation Club, Ho Chi Minh City

AUGUST 2019 - JANUARY 2021

- Organized a Humanoid Robot Contest 2019.
- Organized a Conference about Science, Technology, Robotics & Automation 2019.
- Electronic introductory training for first-year students.
- Assisted with the recruiting and interviewing of new members.

## Education

# Bachelor, Ho Chi Minh University of Technology, Ho Chi Minh City

NOVEMBER 2014 - JUNE 2018

- · Control Engineering and Automation.
- Graduate with good rank.
- · Graduated thesis: "Study And Build An Underwater Robot".

#### Contact



A Male

13/9 Tran Van Hoang Street, 9 Ward, Tan Binh District, Ho Chi Minh City, Viet Nam

+84383191679

thanhhaipif96@gmail.com

#### Links

f

https://www.facebook.com/profil e.php?id=100005415319191

https://github.com/thanhhaibk96

Вē

https://www.behance.net/thanhhichu

in

https://www.linkedin.com/in/than h-hai-chau-816119131/

### Skills

Software Used: Altium, Solidwork

Microsoft Office

**Teamwork** 

Communication

Leadership

**Creative Thinking** 

Time Management

# Languages

English

### Hobbies

Reading Books, Sports (Gym, Soccer), Listening to Music, Traveling.

#### Master, Ho Chi Minh University of Technology, Ho Chi Minh City

NOVEMBER 2018 - NOVEMBER 2021

- Control Engineering and Automation
- Graduate with good rank
- Graduated thesis: "Implementation Of Sliding-Mode Controller For Underwater Vehicle In Horizontal Plane"

#### Extra-Currilar Activities

Member at Project - C of Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City: "Study And Build 600W Thruster For Underwater Robot", Ho Chi Minh City

OCTOBER 2017 - APRIL 2018

- Designed of H-Bridge for 600 Brush-less DC Motor.
- Programming C for STM32F1 Micro-controller.
- Designed of Graphics User Interface using C#.

Leader of An Electronic Team at Project - B of Vietnam National University Ho Chi Minh City: "Study And Build Autonomous Underwater Vehicle For Military Applications", Ho Chi Minh Citv

NOVEMBER 2018 - OCTOBER 2021

- Managed and assign work to the electronic team.
- Designed of electrical boards for robot.
- Programming C/C++/C#/ROS.
- Experienced in using embedded PC such as: Raspberry, Jetson Nano and STM32F4 Micro-controller.
- Experienced in Embedded Linux.

## Courses

Signal and Power Integrity Simulation, HiTech Education

APRIL 2021 - DECEMBER 2021

### References

Dr. Ngoc Huy Tran from Ho Chi Minh University of Technology



